Tom Bremer / Web Developer

tom@tbremer.com • https://tbremer.com

About

I am a web developer and user advocate. I believe in making the web accessible, performant, and easy to use. My professional development experience extends into the mobile and native mobile world (ReactNative) and includes deployment and automation infrastructure. I make time for both individual contribution and leadership responsibilities as a mentor, teacher, and skill-building specialist.

Find Me Online

- github / tbremer
- codepen / tbremer
- linkedin / tom-bremer

Work History

Lead Frontend Engineer, World Wide Technology

2015-07-06 - Present

Frontend Engineer, Mentor.

- Build, test, and deploy web and mobile applications that met client requirements while maintaining best practices related to accessibility and web performance.
- Coach and train teams, individual contributors, and clients with a range of experience in JavaScript/Typescript runtimes (browsers, nodejs, and deno), CSS (PostCSS and Sass), HTML, WCAG accessibility guidelines, performance tuning, and design systems.
- Created and facilitated various training activities including an in-person/remote two day ReactJS deep-dive.
- Worked with the wider WWT Leadership group to build a career matrix, promotion process, and update the Frontend Engineer, User Research, and UX

Software Engineer II, Answers.com / Multiply

2013-04-15 - 2015-06-30

User Experience developer, A/B Test Engineer, UX Tech Stack

- Integral in full site redesign and on-going maintenance of the design system including developer workflows with GruntJS, frontend framework/pattern library used by fullstack engineers.
- Contributed to CSS and Sass based solutions to eliminate JavaScript based DOM manipulations and animations
- A/B test engineer with experience in content variance, performance tuning (pagespeed, TTFB, TTL, first meaningful paint, and time to interactive), and user experience optimizations, including creating long-lived tests on new and existing websites.

Skills

Frontend Development

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Accessibility, NodeJS/Deno, Preact/React.

Web/App Development

NodeJS, React/ReactNative, Rust, OCaml/ReasonML, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Cypher, neo4j, nginx, Docker.

Education

Fine Arts, Bachelor, University of Missouri Saint Louis

Sep, 2006 - May, 2012